A Finding Aid to the Eric Gugler Papers, 1889-1977, in the Archives of American Art AAA.gugleric
Archives of American Art
Eric Gugler papers
1889-1977
AAA.gugleric
Archives of American Art
34.2 Linear feet
The papers of architect and painter Eric Gugler measure 34.2 linear feet and date from 1889-1977. Found within the papers are biographical materials, including papers relating to the Gugler family, personal and business correspondence, writings, project files for commercial and residential commissions, personal business records, photographic materials, including 180 glass plate slides, and artwork.
Gugler, Eric, 1889-1974
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The papers were donated in 1977 by Gugler’s wife, Anne Tonetti Gugler. Additional materials were donated between 1979 and 1980 by Gugler’s business associate, Ferdinand Eiseman.
Related Archival Materials note
The White House Historical Association’s Office of the Curator holds additional Eric Gugler Papers related to the expansion and redesign of the West Wing in 1934.
Conditions Governing Access note
Use of original papers requires an appointment and is limited to the Archives' Washington, D.C. Research Center. Glass plate slides are housed separately and closed to researchers. Contact Reference Services for more information.
Biographical/Historical note
Architect and painter Eric Gugler (1889-1974) lived and worked in New York City, New York. Known for his work on monuments and memorials, Gugler was selected by President Roosevelt to head the redesign and building of the White House’s West Wing in 1934.
Born in Milwaukee, Wisconsin to lithographer Julius Gugler and his wife, Bertha Bremer, Gugler attended Columbia University and received a three year scholarship to continue his studies at the American Academy in Rome. In 1919, he opened his architectural firm on Park Avenue in New York City and began accepting residential and commercial commissions. In addition to designing buildings and houses for clients, Gugler also completed smaller design objects for ceiling details, sculptures, murals, and decorative structures. In the late 1920s and early 1930s, his firm won commissions to complete World War I Memorials in New York and Chicago, Illinois, and also received a major commission to design the Educational Building in Harrisburg, Pennsylvania. Around this time, Gugler married Broadway actress and dancer Anne Tonetti and designed a second residence in the artist’s community of Sneden’s Landing, New York.
Gugler’s interest and willingness to work on large scale memorials and institutional buildings aided in his appointment to a number of prominent commissions in the 1930s to the 1950s. These include the design of the White House’s West Wing and the Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial in Italy, new construction and renovations to the Forman School (Conn.) and Wabash College (Ind.), and the building of residential houses for Katherine Cornell, Barry Faukner, and Paul Manship. In the 1960s, he was selected to head memorial designs for the Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Theodore Roosevelt Memorials in Washington, D.C., and also spent considerable time and energy developing the “Hall of Our History" project. Gugler remained active designing and working on projects until his death in 1974.
Scope and Contents note
The papers of architect and painter Eric Gugler measure 34.2 linear feet and date from 1889-1977. Found within the papers are biographical materials, including papers relating to the Gugler family, personal and business correspondence, writings, project files for commercial and residential commissions, personal business records, photographic materials, including 180 glass plate slides, and artwork.
Biographical materials include certificates, official documents, curriculum vitae, and histories of the Gugler family. Correspondence consists of professional letters regarding prospective and active projects, and personal correspondence from friends and family, including Eleanor Roosevelt, Katherine Cornell, and Paul Manship. Writings include book proposal drafts, essays, notes, speeches, and writings by others.
Project files consist of correspondence, architectural sketches, blueprints, and photographic and printed materials related to Gugler’s work on commercial, residential, governmental, and memorial commissions. Renderings of specific design objects, sculptures, and Gugler's collaborative work on preservation efforts are also included.
Personal business records include correspondence related to Gugler's firm, including office leases, prospective client lists, and service fees. Printed material consists of clippings, exhibition material, postcards, and other miscellaneous items.
Photographic materials are of Eric Gugler and members of the Gugler family. Artwork includes sketches, watercolors, paintings, photographs of artwork, and artwork by Frida Gugler.
Arrangement note
The collection is arranged as 8 series. Glass plate slides are housed separately and closed to researchers, but listed where they fall intellectually within the collection.
Series 1: Biographical Material, 1898-1975 (0.5 linear feet; Box 1, OV 33)
Series 2: Correspondence, 1906-1974 (4 linear feet; Boxes 1-5, 20, OV 33)
Series 3: Writings, 1932-1973 (16 folders; Box 5)
Series 4: Project Files, 1889-1977 (28.2 linear feet; Boxes 5-18, 20-24, 70-72, OV 25-31, OV 33-49, RD 50-69)
Series 5: Personal Business Records, 1928-1972 (0.3 linear feet; Box 18)
Series 6: Printed Material, 1923-1977 (0.3 linear feet; Boxes 19, 24)
Series 7: Photographic Materials, 1890-1966 (9 folders; Box 19)
Series 8: Artwork, 1895-1970 (0.4 linear feet; Box 19, OV 32)
Cornell, Katharine, 1893-1974; Gugler, Frida; Manship, Paul, 1885-1966; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962; Architects as artists--New York (State)--New York; Architects--New York (State)--New York; Architecture, Modern--20th century; Architecture--Designs and plans; Blueprints; Glass plate negatives; Painters--New York (State)--New York; Paintings; Photographs; Sketches; Watercolors
- Biographical Material, 1898-1975; Series 1; 0.5 Linear feet Box 1, OV 33
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical material includes certificates, official documents, curriculum vitae, and documentation of the Gugler family, including grandfather and sisters, Heinrich, Frida, and Gretchen Gugler.
  Arrangement note
  Materials are minimally arranged by document type.
  - Address Book, circa 1950-1960 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Calender, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Certificates, Forms, and Memberships, 1930-1944 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Curriculum Vitae, circa 1930-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Curriculum Vitae, Printed Material, 1939-1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Passports and Travel Documents, 1924-1963 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Will, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Gugler Family Cemetery Plot, circa 1955-1969 (Box 1, Folder 8-9)
    Oversized material housed in OV33.
  - Gugler Family History, circa 1903-1960 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Gugler, Heinrich, 1910-1943 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Gugler, Frida, 1898-1975 (Box 1, Folder 12-14)
  - Gugler, Gretchen, circa 1966 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Oversized Headstone Designs from Box 1, Folder 9, circa 1955-1969 (Box OV 33)
- Correspondence, 1906-1974; Series 2; 4 Linear feet Boxes 1-5, 20, OV 33
  Correspondence consists of three subseries to reflect the original arrangement of letters: correspondent, business, and personal. Correspondent letters are to individuals or businesses with whom professional relationships had evolved into more personal ones and include the American Academy of Rome, the Tiffany Foundation, Eleanor Roosevelt, Katherine Cornell, and Paul Manship. The business and personal subseries include both incoming and outgoing letters.
  The series is arranged as 3 subseries. Correspondent letters are arranged by name, and the business and personal subseries are arranged chronologically. Typescript letters labeled “duplicates” have been retained in the subseries.
  2.1: Correspondents, 1916-1974
  2.2: Business, 1936-1974
  2.3: Personal, 1906-1974
  - Correspondents, 1916-1974; 2.1
    - Albright, Horace, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - American Academy in Rome, circa 1930-1960 (Box 1, Folder 17-25)
    - American Academy in Rome, 1949-1973 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - American Battle Monuments Commission, 1964-1969 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - American Museum of Immigration, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - American Scenic and Historical Society, 1923-1973 (Box 2, Folder 4-10)
      Oversized material housed in OV 33.
    - Bearzi, Bruno, 1951-1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Bolaffio, Roberto, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Castro, Nash, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Celentano, James P., 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Century Club, 1965-1972 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Clarke, Gilmore, 1970-1972 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Colony, John R., Jr., 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Coordinating Committee of American Agencies in Greece, 1942-1943 (Box 2, Folder 18)
    - Cope, Thomas Pym, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 19)
    - Cornell, Katherine, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 20)
    - Dickerman, Marion, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 21)
    - Faulkner, Barry, 1964-1966 (Box 2, Folder 22)
    - Fraser, James Earle, 1949-1953 (Box 2, Folder 23)
    - Griswold, Ralph, 1970-1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
    - Gugler, Eric, 1951-1968 (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
    - Hancock, Walker, 1971-1974 (Box 2, Folder 27)
    - Harbeson, John, 1972-1974 (Box 2, Folder 28)
    - Herron School of Art, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
    - Husted, Ellery, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 30)
    - James, Micky, 1970-1971 (Box 2, Folder 31)
    - Kimball, Richard A., 1949-1970 (Box 2, Folder 32)
    - Lee, Ronald, 1970-1973 (Box 2, Folder 33)
    - Lincoln Memorial University, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 34)
    - Lo Medico, Thomas, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 35)
    - Manship, Paul, 1928-1972 (Box 2, Folder 36-37)
    - McAneny, George, 1944-1955 (Box 2, Folder 38)
    - McCanliss, Lee, 1931-1968 (Box 2, Folder 39-40)
    - Marlor, Clark, 1973-1974 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Mayor, Hyatt, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Meriden Gravure Company, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Milde, Karl F., 1968 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Milwaukee County Historical Society, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Moore, Charles, 1934-1942 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Moore, William, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Sweet Briar College, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Murphy, Robert Cushman, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - National Council Architectural Registration Boards, 1925-1972 (Box 3, Folder 10-14)
      Oversized material housed in Box 20, Folder 1 and OV 33.
    - National Council for Historic Preservation, 1947-1953 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - National Institute of Arts and Letters, 1941-1952 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - New York State Registration, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1929-1958 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin Delano, 1937-1940 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Sheidow/Rispoli Bronze Corporation, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Syracuse University, 1963-1968 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Tiffany Foundation, 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 22-24)
    - University of California, Santa Barbara, 1967-1973 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - Yale University Art Museum, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - Oversized Renderings from Box 2, Folder 5, 1954-1959 (Box OV 33)
    - Oversized Certificates from Box 3, Folder 13, 1968-1972 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Certificates from Box 3, Folder 13, 1968-1972 (Box OV 33)
  - Business, 1936-1974; 2.2
    - Business, circa 1940-1970 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - Business, 1936-1951 (Box 3, Folder 28-33)
    - Business, 1952-53 (Box 3, Folder 34-40)
    - Business, circa 1953-1957 (Box 4, Folder 1-2)
    - Business, 1954-1957 (Box 4, Folder 3-8)
    - Business, 1958-1960 (Box 4, Folder 9-15)
    - Business, 1961-1974 (Box 4, Folder 16-19)
  - Personal, 1906-1974; 2.3
    - Personal, circa 1910-1970 (Box 4, Folder 20)
    - Personal, 1906-1940 (Box 4, Folder 21-24)
    - Personal, 1941-1959 (Box 4, Folder 25-28)
    - Personal, 1960-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1-4)
    - Personal, 1967-1974 (Box 5, Folder 5-8)
    - Personal (duplicates), circa 1938-1970 (Box 5, Folder 9-10)
- Writings, 1932-1973; Series 3; 16 Folders Box 5
  Writings consist of book proposal drafts, four essays on architectural topics, notes on U.S. history topics, and three speeches, two of which were given at Yale and the Pennsylvania School of Arts. There are also essays by architect Charles McKim and sculptor Sidney Waugh, and a selection of collected quotations.
  - Book Proposal Drafts, circa 1960-1971 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Essay, "About the WPA and the H.A.B.S.", circa 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Essay, "Roman Wolf and the Century [Club]", 1973 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Essay, "Villa Bosco Parasio", 1952-1970 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Essays, On Trees, circa 1932-1934 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Notes, Reference (booklists), circa 1950-1970 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Notes, Reference (Northwest Ordinance), 1942 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Notes, Reference (Washington at Newburgh), 1952, 1958 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Notes, Reference (U.S. History), circa 1945-1970 (Box 5, Folder 19-20)
  - Speech, "Boscobel", 1968 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Speech, Delivered at Pennsylvania [School of Arts?], 1936 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Speech, Delivered at Yale School of Fine Arts, 1936 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - McKim, Charles F., Speech Excerpts, circa 1950-1960 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Waugh, Sidney, "Creedo", circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Quotations, By Others, circa 1940-1970 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- Project Files, 1889-1977; Series 4; 28.2 Linear feet Boxes 5-18, 20-24, OV 25-31, OV 33-49, RD 50-69
  Project files consist of correspondence, architectural sketches, blueprints, and photographic and printed material related to Gugler’s work on commercial schools, institutional buildings, residential houses, governmental buildings, and memorial commissions. Gugler’s work on specific design objects and patents, sculptures, and his collaborative work on preservation efforts on the Octagon House in Washington, D.C. and St. Peter’s in Rome, are also included.
  Significant commissions include the White House Executive Office, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt and Theodore Roosevelt Memorials in Washington, D.C., and the proposed "Hall of Our History" project. There is also substantial documentation of construction and renovations for Wabash College, the Education Building (Harrisburg, Pennsylvania), the Katherine Cornell, Henry Ford, Kent Leavitt, and Gertrude Macy residences, the Sicily-Rome American Cemetery and Memorial (Anzio Cemetery) in Italy, and the Battery Park (New York) and Eleanor Roosevelt memorials.
  The series is arranged as 7 subseries. Materials are minimally arranged by project title within each subseries; typescript letters labeled “duplicates” have been retained. Glass plate slides are housed separately and closed to researchers.
  4.1: Buildings, Commercial, 1913-1970
  4.2: Buildings, Governmental, 1929-1973
  4.3: Buildings, Residential, 1937-1973
  4.4: Design Objects, 1937-1972
  4.5: Memorials, 1929-1977
  4.6: Preservation, 1889-1973
  4.7: Sculptures, 1930-1971
  - Buildings, Commercial, 1913-1970; 4.1
    - Correspondence (duplicates), circa 1960-1970 (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Dalton Schools, 1937-1940 (Box 5, Folder 28)
    - First Presbyterian Church, Elizabeth, New Jersey, 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 29-32)
    - First Presbyterian Church, Elizabeth, New Jersey, 1950-1979 (Box 6, Folder 1-2)
    - Forman School, Litchfield, Connecticut, 1939-1969 (Box 6, Folder 3-15)
      Correspondence. Oversized material related to the Varnelle House and Dining Room redesigns housed in OV 33.
    - Forman School, Litchfield, Connecticut, circa 1939-1969 (Box 6, Folder 16-17)
      Sketches/renderings and photographs. Oversize material housed in RD 50.
    - Frank E. Campbell Funeral Church, New York, circa 1937 (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Green Vale School, Long Island, New York, 1956 (Box 6, Folder 19)
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1957 (Box 6, Folder 20-25)
      Bank loan and budget.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1958 (Box 6, Folder 26-29)
      Construction and contracts.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1941-1953 (Box 6, Folder 30-31)
      Copyright and dossiers.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1952-1958 (Box 6, Folder 32-38)
      Writings (drafts).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1949-1958 (Box 6, Folder 39-44)
      Writings (organizational and press releases).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1952-1954 (Box 7, Folder 1-3)
      Writings (project diary).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1952-1958 (Box 7, Folder 4-6)
      Writings (working committee).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1953-1967 (Box 7, Folder 7-10)
      Writings (essays, interview, memo).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1913-1970 (Box 7, Folder 11-16)
      Printed material and fundraising/background information. Oversize material housed in Box 20, Folder 2; Box 21, Folders 3-4; Box 22, Folder 1; and OV 37.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1941-1958 (Box 7, Folder 17-22)
      Renderings. Oversize inscription renderings housed in Box 20, Folders 3-4; OV 36. Oversized panel renderings housed in Box 21, Folder 2; OV 26; and OV 38.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1958 (Box 7, Folder 23-26)
      Renderings (scrapbook).
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1960 (Box 7, Folder 27-33)
      Photographs.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1958 (Box 7, Folder 34-37)
      Negatives.
    - Hall of Our History, Pine Mountain, Georgia, 1950-1958 (Box 7, Folder 38-39)
      Artwork.
    - Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 40-42)
      Budget and minutes.
    - Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine, 1958-1961 (Box 7, Folder 43)
      Printed material. Oversize material housed in Box 22, Folders 2-3.
    - Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine, 1957-1961 (Box 7, Folder 44-48)
      Renderings/photographs. Oversize renderings housed in OV 25 and OV 34-35. Oversize renderings of trees housed in Box 21, Folder 1.
    - Harvard University, Boston, Massachusetts, 1924-1936 (Box 7, Folder 49)
    - King [Cort] Theater, New York, circa 1950-1970 (Box 7, Folder 50)
    - Lamont Geological Observatory, Palisades, New York, 1962-1967 (Box 7, Folder 51-53)
    - Lighthouse Queens Center, Queens, New York, 1956-1957 (Box 7, Folder 54-56)
    - Masters School, Dobbs Ferry, New York, 1954-1956 (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
    - Museums, Domes, 1956-1963 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Oyster Bay Community Center, Long Island, New York, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - P.C.A. Survival House, New York, 1954 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Rheumatic Fever Research Institute, Mount Kisco, New York, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - School of Practical Nursing, Glen Cove, Long Island, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 8-9)
    - St. John's Church, Lattingtown, Long Island, 1953 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - St. Paul's School, Concord, New Hampshire, 1954-1958 (Box 8, Folder 11-13)
    - Taft School, Watertown, Connecticut, 1955 (Box 8, Folder 14-15)
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1945-1970 (Box 8, Folder 16-18)
      Bills and contract.
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1949-1970 (Box 8, Folder 19-29)
      Correspondence.
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1964-1968 (Box 8, Folder 30-31)
      Estimates.
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1939-1961 (Box 9, Folder 1-2)
      General information and printed material.
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1955-1970 (Box 9, Folder 3-4)
      Renderings/models. Oversize material housed in RD 51.
    - Wabash College, Crawfordsville, Indiana, 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 5-11)
      Photographs/display.
    - Unidentified Projects, circa 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 12-14)
    - Oversized Dalton Schools Renderings from Box 5, Folder 28, 1937-1940 (Box OV 33)
    - Oversized Forman School Renderings from Box 6, Folders 5 and 11, 1939, 1951 (Box OV 33)
    - Oversized Forman School Plans from Box 6, Folder 16, circa 1939-1943 (Box RD 50)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Background Material (timeline) from Box 7, Folder 13, circa 1950-1958 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Background Material (promotional) from Box 7, Folder 13, circa 1950-1958 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Printed Material from Box 7, Folder 13, circa 1950-1958 (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Printed Maps/Charts from Box 7, Folder 15, circa 1915-1970 (Box OV 37)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Renderings (inscriptions) from Box 7, Folder 19, circa 1950-1958 (Box 20, Folder 3-4)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Renderings (inscriptions) from Box 7, Folder 19, circa 1950-1958 (Box OV 36)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Renderings (panels) from Box 7, Folder 20, 1944, 1952 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Renderings (panels) from Box 7, Folder 20, 1944, 1952 (Box OV 26)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History Renderings (panels) from Box 7, Folder 20, 1944, 1952 (Box OV 38)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine Printed Material (scrapbook) from Box 7, Folder 43, 1958-1961 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine Printed Material (promotional) from Box 7, Folder 43, 1958-1961 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine Renderings from Box 7, Folder 44, 1960 (Box OV 25)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine Renderings from Box 7, Folder 44, 1960 (Box OV 34-35)
    - Oversized Hall of Our History/National Freedom Shrine Renderings (trees) from Box 7, Folder 46, 1958-1961 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Oversized Wabash College Plans from Box 9, Folder 3, circa 1955-1970 (Box RD 51)
  - Buildings, Governmental, 1929-1973; 4.2
    - Air Force Academy, Colorado, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Educational Building, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, 1929-1973 (Box 9, Folder 16-20)
      Oversized renderings housed in OV 39. Oversize photographs of ceiling dome housed in Box 22, Folder 4. Oversize photographs of maps (wall murals) housed in Box 22, Folder 5.
    - Educational Building, Harrisburg, Pennsylvania, circa 1930-1940; 180 glass slides (Box 70-72)
    - Oregon State Capitol, circa 1950-1970 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - White House, Executive Office Building, 1934-1972 (Box 9, Folder 22-30)
      Correspondence, rooms and objects.
    - White House, Executive Office Building, 1946-1970 (Box 9, Folder 31-33)
      Writings.
    - White House, Executive Office Building, 1934-1972 (Box 9, Folder 34-36)
      Printed material.
    - White House, Executive Office Building, 1934-1970 (Box 9, Folder 37-39)
      Renderings and photographs/display. Oversize material housed in OV 27.
    - White House, Resettlement Administration, 1934-1938 (Box 9, Folder 40)
    - Oversized Educational Building Renderings from Box 9, Folder 18, 1929-1930 (Box OV 39)
    - Oversized Educational Building Photographs (ceiling) from Box 9, Folder 19, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Oversized Educational Building Photographs (wall murals) from Box 9, Folder 20, 1929-1930 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Oversized White House Plans from Box 9, Folder 37, circa 1934-1938 (Box OV 27)
  - Buildings, Residential, 1937-1973; 4.3
    - Bitter, Mrs. Carl, House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Burden, William, Storage Room, 1955 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Bushell, House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Cheston, Charles S., House, 1954-1955 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Coe, Mrs. W.R., House, circa 1950-1970 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Oversize materials housed in Box 23, Folder 1.